Hello everyone, a very warm welcome to all of you.
You are watching You The Real. I am your
own personal advisor, Ami Sharma. The credit for today's video
goes to this comment by Mr. Durgesh.
Durgesh ji,
thank you very much for your comment. If you all
want to understand the maturity benefit, the benefit, and the eligibility criteria of ICICI Potential Life's Savings Suraksha Plan in detail, then
check the description of today's video. You will
get the link to the video related to this plan.
You know that every video on the channel is
continuously updated according to your suggestions, questions, and comments. So, stay
connected with us. Like, share,
subscribe to the channel, and do
n't forget to turn on all the notification bells. So,
in today's video, we are going to learn about the surrender value of ICICI
Product's Savings Suraksha Plan.
If you have this policy, then
you can get the surrender value only after paying the premium for the first two years continuously.
Before that, you will not get the surrender value.
What will you have to do to withdraw the right and guaranteed surrender value? You will have to
withdraw the guaranteed surrender value.
Along with this, you will have to calculate the cash value
of vested bonus and the cash value
of guaranteed additions. Guaranteed surrender value
means the surrender value of the premium paid by you.
Cash value
means the surrender value of the bonus you have collected. This will be
called cash value and the surrender value of the guaranteed
additions collected in the plan will be
called the surrender value. To
understand how we will calculate the cash value of guaranteed additions, let us
take an example to understand the surrender value of ICICI Potential Life's Savings Suraksha Plan. Let us assume that
Mr. A is 30 years old and
he has taken a policy term of 10 years
and the premium payment term is only
5 years. In such a situation, he wants to pay only ₹000 as premium annually. So for that, the
sum assured on maturity
or the base sum assured will be ₹
6953 and the sub-heading amount will be ₹1
lakh which is 10 times the annual premium.
What will they get? Guaranteed Addition The
rate of Guaranteed Addition will be 5% which will be
applied on the sum added maturity. So what we will do is
we will calculate 5% of ₹6953 here
and multiply it by five
because this is available in the first 5 years of the policy. So
this amount will come to around ₹17382 paise which
we will call as Guaranteed Addition. Now we have to
know about the bonus here. The
simple reversionary bonus in this plan is a
compound reversionary bonus and
not a simple reversionary one. The rate of bonus has been
between 3.5% to 3/5%.
Therefore, we are assuming an average value
of the compound reversionary bonus here.
We are assuming 3%. This will be applied
on the sum added maturity, that is,
it will be applied above ₹6953 if you
calculate it. Now, because the premium has been paid for
5 years, so for 5 years
We will consider the bonus of Rs. 1962 25 paise only here, so
how did we calculate it, in the first year you will calculate it in a
simple way, we will calculate the % of 2695 3 up
to Rs. 2500000, if we calculate the compound reversionary bonus here then this
amount will become Rs. 22962 25 paise, now because it is written in the comment
that I want to surrender after paying for 5 years,
after completing 5 years, then according to our example, the premium of Rs. 1 lakh in 5 years becomes
here,
right, so we will know the guaranteed
surrender value factor for premium here, we are seeing
that the policy years are written, these are
1 2 3 4 5 and 10 11 12 13 14 15 16,
this is the policy term, we have completed 5 years, so
here the GSP factor of 67 paise
i.e. guaranteed surrender value
factor has come or i.e.  That we will calculate 67% of the
total paid analyzed premium. Now
after this we are seeing that the surrender and
outstanding term are written here
which are starting from zero 0 1 2 3 4
5 6 right now how to calculate the outstanding term,
you have to subtract from the policy term the number of
years we have completed,
then we will subtract one more year from it,
right so our policy term is 10 years, we have completed
5 years, we will
subtract one more from it, so our
outstanding term here is 4 years, now
we had taken the plan at the age of 30, so our age will be 30 31 32
33 34 years, on completing 5 years, then the
outstanding term will come
here, 4 and the surrender value factor will come
57.3%. Now
for the calculation that we had to do in the bonus factor, we will
calculate 57.3% bonus, right now when it comes to
guaranteed addition, our outstanding policy
term is 4.  If the policy term is 10 years, then
our 18% here will become the
guaranteed cash value factor
for the guaranteed additions. That will become the guaranteed sender
value factor
for the guaranteed additions. Right, we know all the three factors
and we know all the three values ​​here, so
what will we do, we will calculate 67% here, that is, we will calculate
67% here, i.e., we will calculate 250,000 here, then we will calculate 3296 + 2.25 + 57.3 + 18 + 18 + 19573 ...
Thank you very much, thank you very much, understand one thing
yourself and explain it to others too,
insurance is a protection, protection is
never taken incomplete, okay, if the
information is clear to you then please
like the video, share it and
stay connected with us by subscribing to the channel,
tell us in the comment section on
which topic you want the next video, thank you
all, take care of yourself